Lance Simmons • Full Stack Engineer

Philadelphia, PA 205-218-2121

lancehowardsimmons@gmail.com

github/lancehsimmons • linkedin.com/in/lance-simmons • lancesimmons.dev

As a Software Engineer with a background in a diverse art practice as well as a decade of technical support I seek to bring my passion for sharing in creativity to bear on every aspect of my life. My penchant for finding inspiring new solutions has brought me forward seeking fresh, exciting tools to achieve positive change for myself and my community. Whether it's experimenting with sound, ink and paper, or satisfying needs through software development, I bring all of my skills and energy to bear on the task at hand.

Skills

HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, MongoDB, Mongoose, Git, GitHub, Node.js, SQL, PostgreSQL, Figma, Visual Design

Experience

Sept 2021-Dec 2021

General Assembly Software Engineering Immersive- Software Engineering Fellow

- Developed skills in full-stack development through three-month intensive program
- Worked independently and in teams to build web applications
- **Project 1**: **HEED** Asteroid Cataclysm Tracker. Basic front-end functionality app consuming NASA API Near Earth Object data using html, css, and javascript
- **Project 3**: **Everfree Outdoors** fully functioning MERN full-stack e-commerce prototype with full CRUD built as a team
- **Project 4**: **Roast** A dynamic, precision home coffee roasting log. A full-stack web app providing full CRUD, built on Ruby on Rails and React.

January 2010 - March 2020

Current Designs - Technical Support

- Provided broad tech support including managing request, repairs, firmware updates, troubleshooting, etc
- Tracked bugs in hardware and firmware
- Management and quality control of all stock
- Fulfilled all orders

Education

2021

General Assembly Software Engineering Immersive- certificate of completion, Software Engineering

1998-2002

Savannah College of Art and Design Savannah, GA-BA